Thank you.
You may be seated.
Hallelujah!
Good morning!
I'm joining you in the same atmosphere.
God's Word has the ability to quicken us spiritually.
Tell your neighbour, "God's Word has ability".
[God's Word has ability]
Ability to quicken us spiritually.
God's Word is Spirit.
Because it is Spirit, that is why it has that enablement.
It is not just a matter of...
No, it is beyond that.
When you speak it, it goes.
It cannot stay in your lips.
It goes and does things.
You say, "Let there be light!" - you see the light, because it has ability to quicken us spiritually.
Let's quickly look at the book of John 6.
Let's quickly look at the verse 63 there.
It says, "The Spirit gives life; the flesh counts for nothing."
The Spirit gives life and the flesh counts for what?
For nothing!
The words I have spoken to you – they are full of the Spirit.
This means the Word of God has the ability to quicken us spiritually.
The Word of God is a Spirit that has the ability to develop a spiritual force within our hearts called faith.
"The Spirit gives life; the flesh counts for nothing."
This means the Spirit gives being, the flesh counts for nothing.
"The words I have spoken to you – they are full of the Spirit and life." John 6:63.
This means the Word of God is not just words.
There is Bible language and the language of today.
The Word of God, a Spirit has the ability to develop a spiritual force within our hearts called faith.
What we call faith is something that develops within our hearts.
Take note of that; it is not just "faith in faith, faith in this or that".
We talk of faith in the Word of God, faith in the finished work of our Lord, Jesus Christ.
What we call faith in Jesus, faith in the finished works of our Lord, Jesus Christ
is something that develops within our hearts.
What we call faith...
Because there are faiths in faith, faith in this or that, faith in yourself...
We use the word "faith" like a literal word - no - there is more to that.
You say, "I will do the job by faith" - no, that is not the faith we are talking about here.
"By faith it will go, it will work..." - no, that is not the kind of faith we are talking about.
What we call, "Bible faith" is something that develops within our hearts -
a spiritual force that develops within our hearts.
How does this develop?
If you pay attention to God's Word, I mean, if you pay attention to God,
you will find that faith comes spontaneously, naturally.
If you pay attention - not this kind of attention Attention!...
The attention I'm talking about is attention with all your heart.
If you pay attention to God's Word…
How do pay attention?
By looking at God, looking on God, and meditating on the Word.
How do we meditate on the Word?
If I say, "The more you think..." I'm talking of mediation - it is more than thinking.
When I say, "The more you think..." it is no longer on your situation - on God.
The more you think about what you read, what you see around, what you hear,
the more you become familiar with His voice.
Take note of that.
When I say, "The more you think..." I mean meditation.
The more you think - I am talking of meditation.
Before you can get to meditation you must get through "think, think, think..."
That is meditation - "think, think, think..."
Not think - situation, more think - it is no longer your situation - on God.
Faith comes spontaneously, that is, naturally.
This is why you cannot have faith when you read your Bible the way you read literature.
When you read your Bible the way you read chemistry or physics, you cannot have faith
because faith comes spontaneously.
This is why you cannot have faith when you commit what you read to memory.
You memorise your Bible.
It is good to memorise, it is valuable but it must be an integral part of you.
It is good to memorise.
When you memorise the Bible, it is like storing water in your mouth.
When you want to drink and you store the water in your mouth without swallowing it, it's a waste.
If water remains in your mouth without swallowing it, it is a waste.
In the same vein, when you memorise the Bible without allowing this to be part of you,
to be an integral part of you, it is a waste.
You read your Bible, you begin to memorise the verses.
We memorise our Bible to preach, teach it, not to live it.
To live the Bible is to allow this to be an integral part of us.
Faith originates from God.
It originates from who?
[God.]
God.
It does not originate from ourselves.
This is why when you look around, at yourself, everywhere; you cannot find faith.
You look around, at yourself; you cannot find faith.
Once you realise that God is reliable, faith comes.
Ah! God is great!
It brings faith.
A "slot of faith".
Oh, how did this happen?
Oh, God is great!
It means God is reliable - He gives you a slot of faith.
You begin to develop that faith and it begins to grow more.
Another time; "Oh, I am healed. Glory be to God! It can only be God."
Another plot of faith.
Your faith is growing gradually.
It comes spontaneously.
This is why the theologians, many authors writing about the Bible - they have no faith.
Authors of many books about the Bible don't have faith.
They are well educated, they are authors but they have no faith.
That you have a Bible does not mean you have faith.
That you are a Christian, as you claim, does not mean you have faith.
That you are a bishop, prophet, does not mean you have faith.
That you know Jesus does not mean you have faith until Jesus knows you.
Tell your neighbour, "That you know Jesus does not mean you have faith in Jesus until Jesus knows you."
Yes, that you know Jesus, you preach Jesus and people can see you are a good preacher;
it does not mean you have faith.
... until Jesus knows you.
Jesus can only know us by His faith, not by our faith; by His obedience, not by our obedience;
by His humility, not by our humility.
You see people that are very humble and simple, but it is not of God.
You can see people that are very faithful to you, but not of God.
People can be very obedient, to you - yeah, he is an obedient child - but not of God.
The Bible said it, "These I have given you, not as the world gives them".
Everything Jesus has given, the world can also give the same but with conditions.
If you don't look at it very well you may not know the difference.
This is why today we don't know the difference between this and that.
When it comes to things of the Spirit, we are ignorant.
"These I have given you, not as the world gives them" it means all Jesus is giving out,
the world can give also, but with a difference.
What is the difference?
The difference is the end.
Beginnings may look similar, the middles may look similar, but the end is always different.
The end proves the difference.
The beginning looks| similar, you may ignorantly not know the difference.
The middle - at the same time you may ignorantly not know the difference, because we are desperate.
Because of our desperation we don't know the difference.
Desperate to be this, that, to get there - we don't mind how it comes, how it looks,
since he gave you the same thing.
If the end of what you are doing is not going to be good - it has no meaning.
It is better not to do it at all.
We have seen the end of many.
Beginning - flourish, middle seems to flourish, but the end - crying, lamenting, sorrow.
Our end should not end when we pass on to glory.
Our work should not end when we end the journey.
If not, no one will remember you.
You are living, but the children yet unborn to remember that someone lived before...
But when there is no record once the journey ends - of what value...?
If all the effort of the apostles ended at their time, people like me would not be here today.
They paid the supreme price to bring the Gospel.
Because the Gospel did not end at their time, at the end of they journey -
this is why people like me are still here today to preach the Gospel.
What are you doing that makes you sure and believe that it will not end when your journey ends?
What are you doing?
Ask your neighbour, "What are you doing now that will not end when your journey ends?"
Ask your neighbour, " What are you doing that children yet unborn will live to see?"
Ask your neighbour again.
[What are you doing that children yet unborn will live to see?]
That is the question for you to answer.
What are you doing that children yet unborn will live to see when you end your journey?
Just like in case of apostles - we are children yet unborn at their time.
Today we are seen, we are enjoying the price they paid.
The word "faith" led us to this.
Faith comes spontaneously.
It is not the work of reading, righteousness, sweating or whatever you have done
that brings faith – it comes spontaneously, naturally.
This is why you cannot receive that faith when you read your Bible the way you read literature.
This is why it is difficult for someone to acquire faith after finishing theology school.
It is very difficult.
You acquire that knowledge, but that faith is always difficult to acquire.
When you read your Bible the way you read literature you cannot acquire the faith we are talking about.
Because, like I have said, what we call faith is something that has an ability
to develop a spiritual force within our hearts.
It is beyond ordinary reading.
It must be reading with devotion.
It must be reading with what?
[Devotion.]
With devotion.
Tell your neighbour, "It is beyond ordinary reading – it must be reading with devotion."
Quality time is what we call.
When I say read something with devotion it means read it in your quality time.
In a good time, not in a waste time.
You know we read our Bible at the waste time, when we don't have anything to do, in the time we don't value,
when we are tired.
But the Bible must be read in the quality time, your best time, cherished time, not in the time you are tired,
when you don't have anything else to do, you are about to sleep - no!
So that - your spirit can be at its best.
When your spirit is not at its best and you are reading your Bible, you are wasting your time.
Your spirit must be at its best
because when your spirit is not at its best, you cannot meditate; you can only think.
We think when our spirit is not at its best.
We meditate when our spirit is at its best.
Do you understand the word, "spirit being at its best"?
When there is no burden.
You know, when there is so much burden on us you are worried - so much burden.
Weight on your spirit.
If your spirit is not at its best, it cannot attract the Spirit of God.
If your spirit is not at its best, it cannot attract what?
[Spirit of God.]
It cannot attract the Spirit of God.
Your spirit must be at its best to attract the Spirit of God.
That is, when your spirit is free.
That is what I mean.
For our spirit to be at its best means to be free - free spirit.
When you don't think of anything you are relaxed.
You just look at yourself and smile.
Not looking at yourself and crying.
You know, oftentimes you look at yourself and cry.
You may not necessarily cry but you feel so disgusting - you hate yourself.
Free spirit, let someone say, "Free spirit".
[Free spirit.]
I cannot hear you.
Can you tell me how often you have a free spirit?
Have you actually had a free spirit ever before?
Because it id difficult; you have so much to think about.
You can only have a free spirit when you start your thinking by this:
"If today is my last day on earth, what else?"
Start your thinking from there.
Start your thinking from where?
To have a free spirit you must start your thinking this way:
"If today is my last day on this earth, what would they remember me for?"
Once you start your thinking like that, you find yourself thinking the more...
now meditation comes.
Thinking about it alone will make you forget your situation.
When you come to that understanding, "if today is your last day on earth, what else?",
you will soon understand what free spirit means.
You need free spirit to have faith.
When your spirit is at its best, you are smelling the faith of God.
When your spirit is at its best, it means free spirit; then, you can attract the Spirit of God.
He joins Himself to our spirit to declare us children of God.
He joins Himself to our spirit to heal and deliver us.
"Ha! I'm sick. In Jesus' name - be healed", and you are healed.
It means that the Spirit of God joined Himself to your spirit to heal you.
For the Spirit to join Himself to your spirit, your spirit must be free
and when it's free, then it attracts the Spirit of God.
But when it is not free and is in bondage, trouble - then it attracts the evil spirits.
Tell your neighbour, "Will you allow free spirit?"
[Will you allow free spirit?]
It is your duty to do that.
Jesus will not come to do that for you.
It is your role to do that before the Spirit of God comes.
Jesus will not come to give you a free spirit.
It is your duty to allow this.
You just have to put everything behind you.
Let your past pass and move forward.
Know that there is no one without limitations.
If you say you have a problem - there is no one without limitation.
You may have problem, you may have sickness - other people have other problems.
There is no one on this earth, including even T.B. Joshua - no one without limitation.
When you know there is no one without limitation, you allow a free spirit.
There is no one without limitation.
Tell your neighbour.
[There is no one without limitation.]
I cannot hear you.
Yes.
This limitation makes our journey more valuable, more interesting.
Limitation makes our Christian life more interesting, more valuable.
"I am a Christian without limitation" - you are not a Christian.
Limitation will continue to draw you closer to God.
Fast the more, pray the more, seek His face the more.
Limitation makes us pay attention to God.
Tell your neighbour, "My limitation makes me pay attention to God."
The more I pray, the more I seek His face.
Without limitation there is no need for attention.
What brought you here today?
I'm very sure your coming here is not out of comfort, out of pleasure, out of abundant blessing.
Without limitation your faith is no real faith.
Tell your neighbour, "Without limitation, my faith is no real faith."
Faith works on limitations.
Limitation makes our faith more valuable.
What is your limitation?
Ask your neighbour.
[What is your limitation?]
You can be kind enough to tell your neighbour your limitation.
Can you be kind enough?
Can you be kind enough to tell your neighbour your limitation?
Tell your neighbour, "Can you be kind enough to tell me your limitation?"
[Can you be kind enough to tell me your limitation?]
Let me tell you; if any of your neighbours tells you his own limitations - that is not limitation.
Limitation is something you would never discuss with anyone.
When you tell your neighbour, "This is my limitation" - this is not a limitation, it is your situation.
If anybody is telling you his limitation; he is not telling you his limitation but his situation.
Limitation is something that...
When you are praying to God to remove that limitations, you would be looking around.
When somebody knocks the door... "Hosanna".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can you be kind enough and tell me your limitation?
You will tell me your situation.
Limitation is what actually limits you from eating with Jesus on the table,
from kissing Jesus, you can kiss Him, from understanding His voice.
You don't understand His voice.
When you dream you don't know whether it is a real dream or a nightmare.
We don't understand His voice.
We are not familiar with His voice.
If you are familiar with God's voice, you know when satan is talking and when God is talking.
Voices are always in your heart.
You know, I say, faith has ability to develop a spiritual force within our hearts.
Like you are listening to me now - the word will continue to develop a force within your heart.
You will find yourself being transformed.
That is faith.
It has ability to develop a spiritual force within our heart, called faith.
There is more.
When the Bible says, "Faith comes by hearing the Word of God",
it does not end be saying, "Faith comes by hearing".
To hear the Word of Faith, one must pay attention.
To pay attention is to look at God, look on God and meditate on the Word.
How can we look at God?
When you are listening to the ministers of God, all attention, with all your hearts, you have to pray along.
Like you are looking at me - you have to pray along to understand.
It is not just looking at me to understand, you have to begin to pray along, "God, give me a hearing heart.
Lord Jesus, give me a hearing heart".
While you listen to the word, "Give me a hearing heart".
When the minister of God is preaching or you are at home listening to the Christian channel you say,
"Lord, give me a hearing heart".
Because what you hear must go to your heart.
Because the word of Faith you hear is a spiritual force within your heart.
A hearing heart.
When you pray along like that, when you listen to the word, you have a breakthrough.
It comes spontaneously, it just comes.
Because this very body cannot hear the word of Faith.
There is so much to think about.
Burden - our spirit, our heart is in prison.
You need a free spirit to hear the Word of Faith.
"Give me a hearing heart."
That should be your prayer now.
You begin to "fire on" - "Give me a hearing heart".
Don't wait till it is said, "Let's pray" - no.
Your life should depend on that, "Give me a hearing heart".
May God bless His Word.
[Amen.]
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service